Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Two bridges, one with a static steam locomotive on it. 19.0 x 25.4 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Men; Rivers; Bridges; Railways; Trains; Transportation
- Men standing on either side of a railway track.19.1 x 25.4 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Buildings; Railways; Railways; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Streets/Roads; Fez/Tarboush; Street Lamps; Facial Hair; Hats
- 279 - A studio portrait of two women wearing costumes. 26.7 x 20.4 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Musical Instruments; Tambourines; Group Portraits; Turkey; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Costumes; Women; Photographic Prints
- 342 - Dame Turque ..? (A studio portrait of a woman holding a shisha pipe). 24.9 x 19.9 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Smoking; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Costumes; Regional/National Dress; Carpets/Rugs; Painted Backdrops; French Writing; Egypt
- 166 - Alexandrie, Boulevard de Rosette (now Sharia Fouad). 20.5 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1880 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Alexandria, Egypt; French Writing; Carriages/Coaches; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Street Lamps
- A studio portrait of a person sitting cross-legged, with their feet resting on a cushion. 26.7 x 21.9 cm, Circa 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Carpets/Rugs; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Costumes; Regional/National Dress; Men; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings
- A studio portrait of a man wearing a morning suit and a buttonhole. 29.0 x 19.4 cm, 1896 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Men; Signatures; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tuxedos; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Turkey; Facial Hair; Bow Ties
- 102 - Mosquee du Sultan Ahmed (Sultan Ahmed Mosque/The Blue Mosque). 20.9 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1888-1908 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites
- 2 - Obelisque de Cleopatre a Alexandrie (The obelisk of Cleopatra "Cleopatra's Needle" in Alexandria). 20.1 x 26.8 cm, Circa 1875 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Architecture; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing; Italian Writing; Railways; Alexandria, Egypt
- A portrait of an Effendi seated at a carved wooden desk. 26.7 x 21.7 cm, Circa 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Pens/Inkwells; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Bow Ties; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Hats
- 36 - Grande Cimetiere d'Eyouh (Eyüp Cemetery). 18.7 x 24.6 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Women; Tombs/Mausoleums; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Cemeteries; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Children; Boys; Religious Sites; Group Portraits
- 20 - Porte de Seraskerat (gate of the ministry of War, now the entrance to Istanbul University and Beyazıt Tower). 18.7 x 24.6 cm, Circa 1900 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Istanbul University; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyazit Tower; Beyazit Square, Istanbul, Turkey; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; French Writing; Hats
- A portrait of Artin Miskoyian. 24 x 15.9 cm, 6 May 1930 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Turkish Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Bow Ties; Tuxedos; Men; Istanbul, Turkey
- A woman in elaborate Turkish dress posing with a nargileh. 24.1 x 19.7 cm, Circa 1860 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Smyrna; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Individual Portraits; Women; Izmir, Turkey; French Writing
- Photography teachers at the Imperial Engineering College. 17.9 x 23.9 cm, Circa 1890 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Uniforms; Studio Photography; Fez/Tarboush; Teachers; Universities; Men; Cameras; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats
- Mustafa Celaleddin Bey wearing medals and posing on a bicycle., Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Thessaloniki, Greece; Besiktas, Istanbul, Turkey; Turkish Writing; Bicycles/Tricycles; Photographic Prints; French Writing
- A group portrait of men wearing uniforms and holding swords. 26.6 x 32.6 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Fez/Tarboush; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Men; Group Portraits; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair; Hats
- Workers surrounding a building covered with scaffolding 25 x 33.2 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Animals; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey; Ottoman Writing; Buildings; Architecture; Construction; Workers; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes
- A group portrait of men wearing military uniforms with binoculars. 25.6 x 29.9 cm, Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkey; Guns; Binoculars; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Weapons; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia
- A group portrait of men in military uniforms with cannonballs in the foreground., Undated (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Boys; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Medals/Insignia; Hats; Group Portraits; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Bow Ties; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Cannons; Weapons; Children